Guide to the Rice University Early Land Deeds, Contracts and Related Records, 1830-1969 UA 222
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: Oversize drawers, 144192 (Drawer 129-131)
  - Blueprint - survey showing settlement with laird interests, 1921 (from box 1, folder 8), 144454 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Plat showing right of way between Highway 21 and Bryan-Macy Road (from box 7, folder 16), 144418 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (2) - plats showing transfer of portion of land (from box 3, folder 3, sub-folder 4), 144427 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (3) showing plat of land conveyed to Wilder Dickinson (from box 3, folder 3, sub-folder 5), 144426 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - unsold land highlighted (from box 4, folder 1), 144421 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - easement for storm sewer purposes along South side of Sunset Blvd (from box 63, folder 3), 144206 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - map in connection with development of University Blvd. (from box 63, folder 6), 144202 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Brochure/map of Southgate Subdivision, 1929 (from box 63, folder 6), 144201 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Plat and blueprint - Fraternity home addition (from box 63, folder 9), 144198 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - property bordered by Milam and Clay Ave, Houston (from box 64, folder 2), 144195 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Map - Pujo-Gardiner heirs property, 1958 (from box 3, folder 4), 144422 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - chart construction costs for construction of retaining walls on Smith between Capitol and Preston, 1925 (from box 64, folder 1, sub-folder 1), 144196 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - location of highway guard fence (from box 64, folder 1, sub-folder 1), 144197 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (2) - Easement for sewer adjacent to Greenbriar and University Blvd. (from box 63, folder 7), 144200 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Spreadsheets (2) - rental, Brazos Valley Buick Co. (from box 64, folder 2), 144194 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (2) - Greenbriar Dr. drainage and paving (from box 63, folder 5), 144204 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (6) - sanitary sewer easement, University Blvd @ Greenbriar (from box 63, folder 8), 144199 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (7) - Showing block surrounded by Clay, Louisiana, Polk and Milam in downtown Houston, 1924 (from box 64, folder 2), 144193 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 1)
  - Plat and blueprint showing right-of-way in Allen Parish, 1937 (from box 1, folder 9, sub-folder 2), 144451 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Plat showing route and location of easement, 1942 (from box 2, folder 9), 144434 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Map showing proposed line (from box 2, folder 9), 144435 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - 6 blueprints: Rice Institute tract, 1924 Lots 2,3, 5 & 6, 1924 Sketch showing encroachment of East 1/3 of lot 3 Copy of official map of City of Houston - North of Rice Institute Map showing subdivisions North of Rice Institute Map showing Smith's subdivision and Turner Addition (from box 12, folder 2), 144400 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Sketch showing the W.C. Sypert 1/3 League (from box 18, folder 14), 144351 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Plat showing building layout (from box 12, folder 3), 144399 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint - resurvey of Lurana Allen Survey, 1917 (from box 23, folder 9), 144318 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - 3 Blueprints: Robinson, Jones and Stansbury Survey, Montgomery Co., Different scales, 1920 (2) Part of Montgomery Co. showing Rice lands near Jackson, 1916 (from box 28, folder 7), 144302 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - 2 Plats: Grimes and Montgomery Co., working sketch Map of Robinson, Jones and Stansbury Surveys, Montgomery Co. (from box 28, folder 7), 144301 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Land Grant, William M. Rice, Jr., 1904 (from box 34, folder 5), 144278 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint - map of Tyler County based on 1900 census (from box 36, folder 3), 144275 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint - 7620 volt rural district extension, I & G.N railroad survey no.4 (from box 36, folder 3), 144274 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint - fire control map no. 11, Tyler Co., 1935 (from box 36, folder 4, sub-folder 5), 144270 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprints (2) - plat showing location of right-of-way, 1934 (from box 1, folder 9, sub-folder 1), 144453 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprints (2) - plat showing right-of-way, 1934 (from box 1, folder 9, sub-folder 1), 144452 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprints (6) for right of way through tracts 1-6, conveyed to the Rice Land Lumber Co., 1917 (from box 2, folder 2), 144444 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint - showing right of way for Colfax Company, 1917 (from box 2, folder 1, sub-folder 7), 144448 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - location of public road in Beauregard Parish, La., 1919 (from box 2, folder 1, sub-folder 10), 144447 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Quit Claim Deed for Edward and Ada O'Rourke, 1878 (from box 10, folder 5), 144405 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - map showing land described in deed from E.W. L. Hartman to T.H. Lawrence, 1923 (from box 12, folder 2, sub-folder 6), 144401 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - 3 blueprints: Showing tract to serve Coale Roofing Co., 1936 (2) Survey of lots 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 12, block 503, 1920 (from box 12, folder 3), 144398 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - preliminary design of a filling station (from box 14, folder 3), 144384 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - plans for electric street lighting system, Hixon Electric Co., 1912 (from box 42, folder 2, sub-folder 6), 144245 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - tunnel connecting chemistry building (from box 44, folder 3, sub-folder 8), 144243 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - mat sizes for physical lab and dormitory (from box 43, folder 2, sub-folder 4), 144244 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - 3 Blueprints: Rice Institute spur, 1913 (2) Plat - the road on West line no. 5 - Richmond and Brays Bayou, 1913 (from box 61, folder 1), 144220 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Plat - the road on West line no. 5 - Richmond and Brays Bayou, 1913 (from box 61, folder 1), 144219 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprints (2) - map showing no. 6 and environs, Southampton, Houston, 1923 (from box 62, folder 1), 144216 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - Sunset Rd. and Rice Blvd intersection, 1923 (from box 62, folder 1), 144215 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - Sunset Rd and Rice Blvd., 1923 (from box 62, folder 2), 144213 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Map - Southampton Place development, near Rice Institute (from box 62, folder 3), 144212 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Plan - filling station @ 6453 South Main, 1939 (from box 63, folder 1), 144207 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprints (4) - extension of water mains through campus, 1931 (from box 63, folder 4), 144205 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprints (6) - Development, University Blvd. (from box 63, folder 6), 144203 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Plat showing pasture fence location in Beauregard Parish, 1935 (from box 2, folder 8), 144437 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - Southwest pump station site, 1945 (from box 16, folder 39), 144356 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - existing 6" and 8" Gas Mains through Rice Institute, 1943 (Map-drawer 131, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - specifications for administration building (from box 38, folder 5), 144257 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - specifications for mechanical building (from box 38, folder 2), 144256 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint - specifications for residential hall for men (from box 41, folder 1, sub-folder 8), 144248 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint - specifications for administration building (from box 41, folder 1, sub-folder 9), 145537 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Blueprint - specifications for electric street lighting system (from box 42, folder 2, sub-folder 6), 144246 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Time rolls, 1911 (from box 39, folder 1), 144255 (Box 48)
  - Time rolls (from box 40, folder 1), 144252 (Box 48)
  - Time rolls, 1912 (from box 40, folder 1), 144251 (Box 48)
  - Time rolls (from box 40, folder 2, sub-folder 2), 144249 (Box 48)
- Series IV: Index cards
  - Index cards (Original filing system), 144191 (Box 65)
  - Index cards (Original filing system), 144190 (Box 66)
- Series V: Addenda
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred from Treasurer's Office in 2019.
  - Correspondence, 1991, 2004 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Acquisition of 112.54 acres from David Hannah, 1908-10-24 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Acquisition of 9.734 acres from W. T. Carter, 1908-11-10 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Acquisition of 102.428 and 76.521 acres from G. H. Hermann (original and copy), 1909-02-18 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Acquisition of 31.08 acres, except 5.032 acres previously conveyed to Dupont Powder Co., and 41.88 acres from August Warnecke and Mary Warnecke (copy), 1909-04-13 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Acquisition of 2.139 acres from Equitable Power Manufacturing Co., with deed to Equitable from August Warnecke for same property dated Apr. 22, 1909, 1909-04-26 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Acquisition of 70.5 and 24.48 acres from J. C. League, 1909-05-04 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Acquisition of part of 10-acre tract from Charles Frederick Weber and Johanna Weber, 1910-04-07 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Acquisition of 10 acres from Fraternity Home Co. (copy), 1921-10-22 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Acquisition of 14,474 sq. ft. from San Jacinto Trust Co. (copy), 1923-06-29 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Acquisition of 4,487 sq. ft. of "old Houston Belt & Terminal Railway right of way" from Southgate, Inc. (copy), 1929-11-29 (Box 64, Folder 14)